Rohan Shivajirao Powar

Apartment 19 Glen Easton Lodge Leixlip Co. Kildare, Ireland

W23W6D0

Email: rohanpowar2512@gmail.com

Tel: +353899734895 Nationality: Indian

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rohan-powar-b88949b2/

Summary: MEngSc Mechanical engineering graduate with manufacturing and supply chain management experience and proven organizational and management skills through Analyst and engineer roles in electrical and automobile industry. Currently working with Lasertec on their semiconductor Mask inspection tools.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems	Windows
Software's	AUTO-CAD, Solid-work
Certifications	Six Sigma Yellow Belt
Applications and ERP	Microsoft Excel, BAAN, MFG PRO

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lasertec Corporation, Ireland

Field Service Engineer

April 2022- Present

- · Working on ACTIS system (Worlds most advanced inspection system) at Intel FAB34 customer site
- Minimizing downtimes of Lasertec systems
- Established and managing a local maintenance service structure
- Providing training to other field service engineers as needed
- Effectively communicating with Japan headquarters engineers regarding the product applications, technical issues.
- Participating in sales meeting as required
- · Providing training to customers in usage and maintenance of company products.

Nikon Precision Europe GMBH, Ireland

Field Service Engineer

Jan 2021-Dec 2021

 Worked on Nikons highly complex lithography machines at Intel customer site. I was responsible for supporting all aspects of system support for Nikon step and repeat (NSR) semiconductor lithography systems. Typical support includes successfully performing system installations, standard system set-ups, repair of machines downs, and performing a comprehensive analysis of system performance.

Flextronics Technologies, Pune, India Senior Analyst-Logistics

Nov. 2016-July2019

- To retain the Turnaround Time & Accuracy, I verified & scrutinized; the teams' work that were working with me, to make the activities performed robust.
- Export shipment- Prepared documentation and scheduled export shipments
- Conduct training and mentor newly joined employees to ramp up with Industry standards, communication skills, domain knowledge, Microsoft Excel etc.
- Kaizen Projects- Successfully completed and implemented cost and manpower reduction project
- Felicitated with Platinum Award-Passionate Customer Focus and Intense Collaboration
- Pat on the Back Feb 2017 Award- Strong grasping power and good team player
- ISO Audit-Participated in ISO 9001: 2015 Audit

Eaton Corporation, Pune, India

2016-Nov2016

Eaton Corporation Inc. is an American multinational power management company with 2018 sales of \$21.6 billion, founded in the United States with corporate headquarters in Dublin, Ireland

BOAT Trainee

- Freight Auditing & Forwarding Invoices to Accounts Payable team for Freight Payment.
- Preparing Reports & Claiming amount from Bank under Merchandise Export from India Scheme.
- Scheduling & Tracking of Domestic & International Shipment.
- Preparing Quarterly Reports for Cost spend analysis.
- Project Co-Champion for ITCC (Indian Transport Contract Centralization) Project
- Won 3 Kaizen Award and one from Global Head for Cost Saving

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sinhgad Engineering College, India

Aug 2014- June 2015

President (Student Association)

- · Lead 600 students
- Organized annual events and Workshop and Seminar.
- · Fund Collected for Social Problems
- Represented College at National level for various technical events

EDUCATION

University College Cork (UCC), Ireland

2019-2020

March

MEngSc Mechanical Engineering 2H1 (66%)

<u>Modules:</u> Programming in Python, Python with Data Science Application, Biomedical Systems, and CAD/CAM, Non-Destructive testing, Operations Management, Project Management, Optimization and Continuous Process Improvement, Process Validation and Quality Control, Pharmaceutical Engineering.

Project: Design of Cobot for Flexible Manufacturing

- Design of Cobot with stiffness variable arm, which enables the ability to work with people.
- · Study of various arm for robotic application.

Solapur University, Solapur, India

2010-2015

Bachelor of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering, 1H1 (74.53%)

Equivalent to a Level 8 Honors degree in Ireland according to the National Qualifications Authority of Ireland

<u>Modules:</u> Mathematics, Theory of Machines, Strength of Material Mechatronics, Automobile Engineering Automation and Control Systems, Machine Drawing, Operations Research, Thermodynamics, Stress Analysis

Final Year Project: Solar Powered Multipurpose Agricultural Pesticide Spray Pump

- An innovative solution for farmers alternative, effective, multipurpose and low-cost option
- User should be able to get complete benefit of renewable energy
- Energy storage option which can be used for LED light, Mobile Charging and Mini table Fan

INTERESTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winner of IMech/engineers Ireland "Applied student Engineering Project "competition 2020
- Secured UCC International students' merit-based scholarship worth of 2200 euro
- Won 22 National Prizes in Paper Presentation, Elocution and in Project competition

REFERENCE

Available on request